Bill Dean

314 Whitmore Avenue Toronto, ON M6E2N4

416 556 5238

742designs@gmail.com billdean.me

OVERVIEW

I am a skilled front-end developer who has been building things on the web since 1998. I have extensive experience coding responsive websites with mobile first in mind using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery and WordPress. I possess a passion for learning new technology and strive for clean, semantic code that makes sense.

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer / Systems Support Analyst, Pearson Embanet

Toronto, ON — 2009-present

- Coding and maintaining more than 200 responsive websites using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP and WordPress
- Collaborating with designers to meet business requirements and build websites based on PhotoShop mock-ups
- Debugging and performing QA for code across multiple browsers, operating systems and mobile platforms
- Supporting LAMP servers on AWS. Tasks include setting up new environments, maintaining version control system (SVN) and deploying websites to production
- Automating everyday server maintenance tasks through Bash scripting
- Monitoring incoming support requests through Jira
- Documenting procedures and practices with Confluence

Web Developer, Law Society of Upper Canada

Toronto, ON — 2005-2009

- Worked with clients and content producers to update and maintain public and intranet websites
- Facilitated coding and development to ensure compliance with W3C accessibility standards
- Tested with multiple browsers and platforms including speech and text browsers

Web Designer, Pet Health Inc

Oakville, ON — 2003-2004

- Designed and maintained over forty websites, including front-end development, and graphic creation and manipulation
- Oversaw search engine optimization and paid placement campaigns
- Produced reports on website traffic and other statistics
- Coordinated and designed three monthly e-Newsletters

Communications and Web Facilitator, City of Toronto Cycling Committee

Toronto, ON — 2000-2001

- Designed and developed Cycling Committee website, including HTML coding, graphic design, creating PDF documents and content editing
- Coordinated and wrote monthly online and print newsletters, including coding, design and layout, development of distribution strategy, and management of subscription database

Web Developer/Technical Support Analyst, Pictorius Inc

Halifax, NS — 1998-1999

- Developed/assisted in the development of several Internet and intranet website projects
- Monitored and responded to clients' technical support requests via telephone and email

SKILLS

Languages

- HTML 5
- CSS 3
- JavaScript
- XML
- PHP
- Bash

Libraries and Frameworks

- jQuery
- Angular
- Less
- Sass
- Bootstrap

CMS

WordPress

Version Control

- SubVersion
- Git

Tools

Gulp

Editors

- Sublime Text
- Vim

EDUCATION

International Academy of Design

Digital Media Design Program
Toronto, ON — January 2002 - June 2002

Keyin Technical College

Diploma in Computer Science
Halifax, NS — January 1997 - July 1998
10 week work-term ATV / ASN (Atlantic Canada CTV Affiliate)

St. Francis Xavier University

Bachelor of Arts in Music Antigonish, NS — September 1991 - April 1995